<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The guiltless cries and warnings of the innocent against injustice, oppression, cruelty, false-swearers, envious men, and such like witnesses, arisen up against a plain man, or, A living and true witnesse condemned, through want of sound (yet through unjust) judgment : together with the unequall and unreasonable proceedings of Humphry Wildey, Mayor, and Edward Solley, and Robert Sollers, Aldermen, and Justices of the city Worcester, as may plainly appear by what followeth, besides the unjust sufferings of the guiltlesse ... / from the hand, mouth, and very heart of a true Friend, and not an enemy to the person, or well-being of any man, woman, or childe within thee, O city, or upon the face of the earth, throughout the whole creation of God, or of that which lieth under the cruel bondage of death and corruption, for which I suffer, and labour, and travail, with, and among many brethren, for its perfect freedome, and restauration, into the glorious liberty of the sons of God (as in the beginning), whose servant, witnesse, and prisoner for the elects sake, I am called by men Daniel Baker, by scorners, a Quaker.</title>
            <author>D. B. (Daniel Baker), fl. 1650-1660.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1660</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 42 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 11 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A29607</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing B482B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R22840</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12125431</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12125431</idno>
            <idno type="VID">54582</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A29607)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 54582)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 756:22)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The guiltless cries and warnings of the innocent against injustice, oppression, cruelty, false-swearers, envious men, and such like witnesses, arisen up against a plain man, or, A living and true witnesse condemned, through want of sound (yet through unjust) judgment : together with the unequall and unreasonable proceedings of Humphry Wildey, Mayor, and Edward Solley, and Robert Sollers, Aldermen, and Justices of the city Worcester, as may plainly appear by what followeth, besides the unjust sufferings of the guiltlesse ... / from the hand, mouth, and very heart of a true Friend, and not an enemy to the person, or well-being of any man, woman, or childe within thee, O city, or upon the face of the earth, throughout the whole creation of God, or of that which lieth under the cruel bondage of death and corruption, for which I suffer, and labour, and travail, with, and among many brethren, for its perfect freedome, and restauration, into the glorious liberty of the sons of God (as in the beginning), whose servant, witnesse, and prisoner for the elects sake, I am called by men Daniel Baker, by scorners, a Quaker.</title>
                  <author>D. B. (Daniel Baker), fl. 1650-1660.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>22 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for R. Wilson ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1660.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed: D.B.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Society of Friends.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:54582:1"/>
            <p>THE GUILTLESS CRIES AND WARNINGS of the INNOCENT: AGAINST <hi>INJUSTICE, OPPRESSION, CRUELTY; Falſe-Swearers, Envious Men,</hi> and ſuch like <hi>Witneſſes,</hi> ariſen up againſt A PLAIN MAN. OR, A Living and True WITNESSE condemned, through want of ſound (yet through Unjuſt) Judgment. together with the unequall and unreaſonable Proceedings of HUMPHRY WILDEY, Mayor; and EDWARD SOLLEY, and ROBERT SOLLERS, Aldermen, and Juſtices of the CITY WORCESTER, as may plainly appear by what followeth: beſides the unjuſt Sufferings of the GUILTLESSE. From whom a clear, true Sound, and many certain Warnings, and wholeſome Exhortations, have been, (as a Trumpet) ſounded forth, and directed to the ears and hearts of thy chief Magiſtrate and Rulers, O CITY: together with the multititude of the <hi>Inhabitants</hi> within thy bowells, fenced Walls, ſtrong Holds, Borders, and Territories, O wicked CITY. From the Hand, Mouth, and very Heart of a true FRIEND, and not an Enemy to the Perſon, or well-being of any Man, Woman, or Childe, within thee, O CITY, or upon the Face of the Earth, throughout the whole Creation of God, or of that which lieth under the cruel Bondage of Death and Corruption, for which I ſuffer, and labour, and travail; with, and among many Brethren, for its perfect Freedome, and Reſtauration, into the glorious Liberty of the Sons of God (as in the beginning) whoſe Servant, Witneſſe, and Priſoner for the Elects ſake, I am, Called by men DANIEL BAKER, by Scorners, A Quaker.</p>
            <q>To this end was I born, and for this cauſe came I into the world, that I ſhould bear witneſs unto the Truth. Every one that is of the Truth heareth my voice, ſaith Jeſus, <bibl>
                  <hi>John 18.37.</hi>
               </bibl>
            </q>
            <q>As a Sheep before her Shearers is dumb, ſo he openeth not his mouth. (Lo) he was taken from priſon, and from Judgment, And who ſhall delare his Generation? <bibl>
                  <hi>Iſaiah 53. Ver. 7, 8.</hi>
               </bibl>
            </q>
            <p>Printed for <hi>R. Wilſon,</hi> at the <hi>black-ſpread-Eagle</hi> in <hi>Martins,</hi> 1660.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="account">
            <pb facs="tcp:54582:2"/>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:54582:2"/>
            <head>A COPIE of what was delivered to the Major of the CITY of <hi>Worcheſter,</hi> for Him and the <hi>Aldermen</hi> to read.</head>
            <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <opener>
                     <salute>Friends,</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>IS it not the Honour of a Good Magiſtrate, wiſely, with a Good <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nderſtanding, to make diligent Inquiry, and ſearch into the Nature and Ground of a Matter, or Controverſie between a Man and his Neighbour, that ſo True and Sound Judgment may be miniſtred without Reſpect of Perſons, and that the Cauſe of the Poor may be heard, as well as the Rich; and ſo Judgment, or Sentence to be paſſed according to Equity, and Mercy, that the Sword may be laid in its due Place, (even upon the Head of the Tranſgreſſor) leſt the Guitleſs, (whom God will Juſtifie) be ſmitten, and Equity, Sound Judgment, and Good Lawes be perverted to a wrong end, which will draw down Vengeance, a Curſe, and wrath from the Lord God of Judgment, and not Bleſſing.</p>
                  <p>Hearken ye Rulers, and conſider your Proceedings paſt againſt me, and let the Light of Jeſus in your Conſciences, give Sentence, and anſwer me, whether ye did not reſpect perſons in judgment, (which you ought not) when as ye compelled me to ſtand bare headed at the Bar, and my Accuſer <hi>John VVinnington</hi> ſate upon the Bench, beſide one of your Rulers? And, Whether you did well, after <hi>John VVinninton</hi> had ſpake forth the Words of his Falſe Teſtimony the firſt time, and varied in his Second Speech, contrary to his first, which I immediately ſhewed you, but ye did not heed it, but ſuffered, or cauſed a Pen, Ink, and Paper to be given to the Falſe Witneſs, to write down what he pleaſed, as he ſate by one of you upon the Bench: And, if ye remember, I queſtioned, Whether it were according to the Law of the Nation, what ye ſuffered him to do then, the matter being ſo weighty, as I laid it before you, ſaying, For ought I know, my Life lay as it were at the ſtake?</p>
                  <p>And, Is this a Shame, or an Honour to you Rulers? Conſider
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:54582:3"/> of it: And I cry even unto You, Repent while Ye have a Day, and quit Your Selves like Men of Truth, fearing God, to clear the Guiltleſſe, and Your Selves alſo, while ye have time, and it is in your power: But this I tell you in plainneſſe, That if Deliverance come ſome other way, the Weight of Falſe Judgment and Guilt will lie heavy upon your Conſciences, before the Lord God in his Day, and of your Account.</p>
                  <p>Conſider, I ſay, whether ye have done well, or whether ye have not had reſpect of Perſons, in Judgment, and condemned the Guiltleſſe, when Ye had an Opportunity put into Your hands, to do Juſtice, and Judgment, which I expected from You: But Behold Oppreſſion, and the Needy is turned aſide from Judgment: And, Is it not Joy to the Juſt to do Judgment? but Deſtruction ſhall be to the Workers of Iniquity, ſaith Wiſedome; and Wo unto them that ſeek deep to hide their Counſell from the Lord, whoſe Works are in the dark, and they ſay, Who ſeeth us? Surely, Your turning of things upſide down, ſhall be eſteemed as the Potters Clay, See <hi>Iſaiah 29.15, 16.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <closer>
                     <dateline>Worceſter <hi>Priſon,</hi> 
                        <date>
                           <hi>this 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Month, the 24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day, 1660.</hi>
                        </date>
                     </dateline>
                     <signed>
                        <hi>From the hand of a Lover of the whole Creation of God, whoſe Priſoner I am,</hi> D. B.</signed>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>Hearken, You that are called Chriſtians, and profeſſe the Scripture your Rule, and <hi>Pauls</hi> words, that read this; <hi>Foelix</hi> (whom ſome call a Heathen) was ſo noble to <hi>Paul</hi>) when he was a Priſoner, commanded to let him have Liberty, and that none of his acquaintance ſhould be forbidden to miniſter, or come unto him. Now, If any be ready to ſay to me, Thy Caſe is not <hi>Pauls.</hi> My Anſwer is, <hi>Paul</hi> was innocent of the things he was falſly accuſed of; and ſo am I, God is my Witneſſe, whether Men believe or not; and, Let ſuch, called Chriſtian Governours take heed, leſt thoſe called Heathen Rulers ariſe up in Judgment, againſt them, and condemn them.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>The</hi> Sheriffe <hi>had a</hi> Coppie <hi>of this.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:54582:3"/>
            <p>The SHERIFF ſent ſundry times ſince, to order that I may have more Liberty, as to let Friends come to me, the City Hall being as it were under my Priſon-Chamber, I having ſometime Liberty to go down; and once, when the Juſtices were preſent upon the Bench, I ſpake theſe words to them, and ſaid, Bleſſed ſhall they be that without Reſpect of Perſons do Juſtice, and Judgment, but Eternall Wo from the Living God will be on them that do it not; and they ſhut me up more cloſe.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="letter">
            <head>To the <hi>Major,</hi> and for the <hi>Aldermen</hi> to read alſo.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>Friend,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>TAke heed (as thou wilt anſwer before the Throne of the Majeſty on High, even the Lord God of Judgment, who from Generation to Generation did and doth, and yet will plead the Cauſe of the Guiltleſſe, whether men do it or not) that thou yet purſue not Evil to thine own Deſtruction, in conſenting to, or joyning with any in Teſtimony, or Judgment, againſt the Innocent, leſt the weight of innocent Blood lye heavy upon thy Conſcience: The Living God, (behold I teſtifie) hath an Eternall Witneſſe, that is true, in thy Conſcience; And in love, (whether thou hear or forbear) I warn thee alſo, that thou take heed of juſtifying any thing, or Witneſſe, or Teſtimony, which the Everlaſting Witneſſe, (the Light of Jeſus) in thee condemns; or, on the contrary, that thou perſiſt not to condemn any thing which the Pure and True Witneſſe of the God of Truth in thee juſtifyeth: For he was a wiſe Man, that ſaid by the Spirit of the Lord, <hi>He that condemneth the Juſt, and justifieth the Wicked, even They both are an Abomination to the Lord.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And, O Ye Rulers, wiſely conſider, whether you are ſo, or a praiſe to the Lord, who is our All, God, bleſſed for ever. I commend my Teſtimony freely to the witneſſe of God in Your conſciences, to be anſwered in the Day of God whether you now hear or forbear: Know Ye, that I am a Servant of the Living God, and a Friend, and not an Enemy to any one mans Perſon, upon the Face of the whole Earth, therefore not an enemy to the
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:54582:4"/> King God is my Witneſs, that I am a Friend alſo to ſound Juſtice, and Judgment, Good Magiſtrates, Good Government, Good Lawes, and am ſubject to every Ordinance of Man for the Lords ſake, called of men, (who am clear of Your Guilt, and Falſe Accuſations, and Swearings.)</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>DANIEL BAKER, <hi>by</hi> Scorners <hi>called</hi> QUAKER.</signed>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Worceſter</hi> Priſon, <date>This 22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> of the 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Month, 1660.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>From the Lords Priſoner for the Teſtimony of Truth. <hi>D. B.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="letter">
            <head>To the MAYOR of the CITY. <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <salute>Friend,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>FOr ſo much that thou art choſen and called MAYOR, or Chief Magiſtratte of the CITY, bear with me a little, and ſuffer the eye and ear of a good and perfect underſtanding (in the Spirit of Meekneſs, as a Man of Truth) to be opened in thee, that from henceforth, if haply the Almighty God (in whoſe hand thy breath is) lengthen the Dayes of this Life, to the end thou mayſt glorifie, fear, and honour him only, that thou alſo mayſt be honoured with the true honour, which comes from him who is the Eternal Fountain of Life; for which end Life and Breath is freely given to all men; and not that any man, or any in the Authority of God, (eſpecially of them called Chriſtian Magiſtrates) ſhould diſhonour him, or turn aſide the needy from (or have reſpect of Perſons in) Judgment, or condemn the Juſt, and juſtifie the Wicked, or hearken to Lies; neither to let a Falſe Witneſſe go unpuniſhed; or to do, ſpeak, or act, or conſent to any of theſe, or ſuch like Abominations. And Friend, let me ask thee again, Was not he a wiſe Man, that ſpake by the
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:54582:4"/> Spirit of the Lord in his Wiſdom, ſaying, <hi>He that Condemneth the Juſt, and he that Juſtifieth the Wicked, even they both are an Abomination to the Lord?</hi> (Mark that) who is my Witneſs, that I am as Innocent, and as clear (whether thou canſt beleeve me or nay) even as a ſuckling Child.</p>
            <p>Now in the fear and dread of the living God (who is higher than the higheſt) Conſider whether thou, O man, and them that ſate on the Judgment Seat by thee, have been a praiſe to God, to good, juſt, reaſonable men; or not a good ſavour in your Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceedings: And concerning the matters falſly Charged againſt me, which as yet you have not Condemned, and the very Truth and Reaſon is through neglect, or for want of making diligent Inquiry and Search into the Nature and Ground of the matter, as it becomes men of Truth ſo to do; but on the contrary, have you not Juſtified evil envious men, that fear not the true God, by caſting my Body into Priſon, and, as it were, gladly recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving falſe Teſtimonies from falſe Swearers and ungodlike men, as it were in the dark, and behind my back alſo? and this was not right, when as the Accuſers, and the Accuſed, men of Truth, would have cauſed to appear face to face; and ſome called Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>then Rulers, ſtand Juſtified before the Lord, and in the ſight of good men, in ſuch matters; But behold how you have erred in this matter, and Lo its not hid from the God of Heaven, who will certainly bring you to Judgment, and plead the Cauſe of the Guiltleſſe, and not Condemned; although ye do, and yet may (through evil counſel, prejudice or enmity, which pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeds not from the Spirit of Life of Innocency) make light of, and condemne it.</p>
            <p>Wherefore I yet Cry to you, Repent, and ſuffer Gods faithful and true Witneſſe, even the Light of the Lord Jeſus, in every of your Conſciences, to ariſe and anſwer me; for to that only can I freely commend my Teſtimony, becauſe even in that, true and ſound Judgment is placed: And, O ye Rulers, how well would it be with you, were ye in all things ſubject to, and freely guided by it; even in you, and in all men its to have its Authority and Preheminence, to Guide, Order, Direct and Teach them in all true, ſound, right, wholſome words, wayes and actions. For according to its Teſtimony in every man (Male or Female)
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:54582:5"/> which is, was, and for ever will be the ſame (to wit Truth) ſo ſhall every mans Words, Thoughts, Wayes and Actions be Tryed and Judged, Juſtified or Condemned, according to the Nature, End and Ground of all the Deeds done in the Body (of Male or Female) for this is the everlaſting Truth, from which I ſpeak.</p>
            <p>And its an undeniable ſaying (to wit) That evil is joyned to within, before it come forth either into Word or Action: Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I Cry in the dread of the living God, Let all be warned to cleave to the Good, and eſchew, or abſtain from the Evil in its firſt appearance; for certainly, ſo ſhall be the reward of every man (Male or Female) And this is not contrary, but accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the true and faithful ſayings of Jeſus, and the holy Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures of Truth, <hi>And lo, every Tongue ſhall confeſs to the Equi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Juſtice of the Pure God (who is Light) and to the Spiritual and Eternal Light of the Lord Jeſus, the faithful and true Witneſs, Gods Righteouſneſs that Juſtifieth not, but Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demneth the ſin where it is joyned to, or conceived (to wit) in the fleſh, where the Prince of Darkneſs of the power of the Air hath his Seat or Throne; but the Light of the Lord Jeſus re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veals, or makes him manifeſt, and comes to Diſ-throne, Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn, and Deſtroy both him (to wit) the Devil and his works in man.</hi> And behold, theſe are the true and faithful ſayings of the living God, Whether you, O you Rulers, or any to whom this ſhall come, can receive or beleeve them or not, or hear or forbear; Lo, its love to the Meek, Innocent Spirit, yet Oppreſſed and Impriſoned, even in you, of which this Body, in which I am, is a true figure, if ye can read with a good and noble Underſtan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding, and beleeve in the Truth, which yet lieth hid in you, and if you have Ears to hear, you may hear the Cry of the Poor and Needy, the Priſoner of Hope, the Oppreſſed within and without you, whoſe Cauſe is but one, which the God of Heaven will certainly Plead, whether the lofty Oppreſſors hear, or for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bear.</p>
            <p>And <hi>Friend,</hi> Behold I yet call unto thee, to hear me patiently, who have had Four or Five falſe Witneſſes aroſe up againſt me, and have laid things to my Charge, which was not in my heart (concerning which I am as a Babe) And I know thou, O man,
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:54582:5"/> and you, before whom I did appear the 20th Day of the 8th Month, are not altogether Ignorant of it, that its even ſo: And lo, I ſay again, They have Sworn, and laid ſuch things to my Charge, which I knew not; neither came ſuch ſayings into my heart (or mind) from which I ſpeak the Truth, even from my very heart (the moſt true living God, who ſearcheth it, is my witneſs) before you Rulers.</p>
            <p>And if ſo, thou, O man, hadſt been faithful to the Light, or true Teſtimony of God in thy Conſcience, it would not have ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fered thee to have Condemned, or at leaſt to have Conſented to the thing in condemning the Guiltleſs, of which thou are found truly guilty of, and others with thee, before the Lord of Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven, although ye may ſeem to hide it, as it may be, before men; yet verily the moſt ſecret works of Darkneſſe cannot be hid from the Eternal Eye that beholds all the ſecret Actions of the ungod<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like men, that cannot ſave you from the Terrors of the dreadful God, or from the terrible ſtroke of his Hand, when it is lifted up to ſmite, or from the Arrows of the Almighty, when his Bow is bent, or from the glittering powerful Sword of his Strength, who is the mighty God of <hi>Jacobs</hi> life, the plain man that dwelt in his Tent, and as a Prince prevailed with the moſt High; who, if he put forth but his Finger, when his long-ſuffering, as it were, is come to an end, and then ſmite the life of your va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity. Alas, Wo, and Alas for you, you are but men that ſhall die, and come to Judgement before the Throne of Gods Lamb, ſlain ſince the Foundation of the World of the un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>godly.</p>
            <p>Wherefore I cry unto thee, O man, and unto you, O Rulers again, That you ſuffer the fear and dread of the living God to poſſeſſe and be ſet up even in your hearts, and by it ſee that you Repent, and bring forth Fruits meet for Repentance, leſt you die in your ſins. If ſo, then eternal Wo and Torment will be your Portion, with the Beaſt and falſe Prophet, in the Lake that burns, where all Lyars, and falſe Accuſers, and Swearers, and Drunk<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ards, and all that forget God, ſhall be turned together with the fearful and unbelieving, Covetous, Idolaters, ſhall have their part in the ſame.</p>
            <p>Wherefore <hi>Friend,</hi> and <hi>Friends,</hi> ſee you to it from henceforth,
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:54582:6"/> Behold, I warn you freely, in the name of the Lord, as formerly, whether ye can believe me, or nay, (viz.) That Ye juſtifie not any thing in any caſe or controverſie, between Brother and Brother, Neighbour and Neighbour, whether Poor or Rich, and not to have reſpect to Perſons, to pervert ſound Judgment, which the faithfull and true witneſſe of God in your conſciences condemns, or teſtifieth againſt: Or, on the contrary, that You in the leaſt, or in any wiſe joyn not in Judgment with any falſe witneſſe, Lyar, or Swearer, although they are or may be never ſo High, or Potent in the Earth; to turn aſide the Needy from Equity, Mercy, and ſound Judgment, or to condemn the Poor and Needy, the Innocent and Guiltleſſe, that cannot ſwear, nor lye, nor reſpect Perſons, but keeps in the Doctrine of Chriſt, in whoſe mouth was found no guile, and is a perfect Example to him in theſe things, neither can he give flattering Titles to any man, or ſecretly reſpect the perſon of any man, but ſpeak the Truth from his very heart, though it may return to his own hurt: Such a one doth and will the God of Heaven and Earth juſtifie, (and plead, and not condemn) his cauſe from Generation to Generation, even for ever: although unreaſonable men, through unmercifulneſſe, prejudice, Enmity or falſe Judgment, may condemn the Generation of the Righteous, yet will not the Lord, who is my God, who judgeth righteouſly. And know thou, O man, and hearken ye Magiſtrates of this City, <hi>Worceſter,</hi> and liſten, O all ye Inhabitants within the bowells thereof: Behold, I have Freedome and alſo boldneſs, in the Eternall Truth of the Living God, where I dwell, to give forth theſe words of my Teſtimony. And, Know ye, that my Innocency is a true and living VVitneſs againſt the Man of Enmity, (and them that joyned with him) who ſo wickedly, a Falſe VVitneſſe, with many others are ariſen up againſt me, and having not the fear of the true God before their eyes, have impudently forſworn themſelves againſt me.</p>
            <p>And, as concerning the matter, <hi>Iohn Winnington,</hi> ſo wickedly and falſly hath ſworn, who is known to be a diſorderly ungodlike man, as, That I ſhould ſay, concerning <hi>CHARLES</hi> the late, ſecond King of <hi>England,</hi> as I paſſed along the Streets of the <hi>City,</hi> is wickedly falſe; and that I ſaid not theſe words,
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:54582:6"/> it is true, and I am innocent. He that ſearcheth mine and every mans heart knoweth, I ſpeak Truth from my heart, that its even ſo, as I alſo declared in the preſence, and before the faces of you Rulers; and that I am as a babe of Yeſterdayes bringing forth, concerning this falſe Charge of the Envious man, with the Reſt, which alſo are as falſe as the former. And contrary to this behold I give forth my Teſtimony, And let the Inhabitants throughout the Land, and of the whole Earth know, That this is our ſure, ſound, ſteadfaſt, and eternall Principle, for which we have ſo deeply ſuffered on every hand hitherto, ſince we were a People, raiſed up by the Almighty Arm of the Lord, who is the Everlaſting Light, and Salvation of us, that Chriſt Jeſus is the true Light that lighteth every man that cometh into the World; and that a manifeſtation of this true, Holy, Spirituall, and Eternall Light, or Spirit of the Everlaſting God, who is Light, that a manifeſtation of it is given to every man, to profit withall, and that it is in every man that cometh into the world, and well ſhould it be with all men in whom it comes, or may come, to have its Right Noble, and honourable Authoriy, and Preheminence; otherwiſe it cannot go well with them.</p>
            <p>And another, a Baptiſt ſo called, according to the Depoſition written, hath falſly ſworn, (although ſome of his fellowſhip owned him not in this matter) ſaying, <hi>He rode about the ſtreets,</hi> when as I had not paſs'd through one Street, as afore expreſt, <hi>ſaying, moſt of the Inhabitants of this City was in a worſe condition than Turks and Heathens, except they repented:</hi> Now, as to theſe words, they do ſomewhat agree to the words of my Teſtimony, ſounded forth in the City. And again, <hi>Winnington</hi> falſly ſwore, as the other, <hi>(Marke)</hi> that he heard me ſay, <hi>That this City would be as a Sodom and Gomorrah, or words to this effect:</hi> This alſo is falſe. But, what if I had ſaid ſo? Was the crying ſinnes of <hi>Sodom</hi> and <hi>Gomorrah,</hi> that ſuffered the vengeance of Eternall Fire, greater? Let the Wiſe in heart conſider and judge, and let all be warned, as once and again, yea and many times, (within thy Cities and Towns, and chief Places of concourſe <hi>(O England.)</hi> In ſingleneſs and uprightneſs of my heart, in obedience to the Lord of Heaven, with my precious life
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:54582:7"/> in my hand, which often, through the loving kindneſs of the Lord, I have received power to lay it down, and to take it again, according to the perfect Example of the Captain of my Salvation, and Elder Brother, to cry Repentance: I ſay it to the end, that all may be warned to bring forth fruits meet for Repentance unto life, as it becometh all that make mention of the Name of the Lord, which I alſo freely cryed within thy Gates (O City). And what is this Crime worthy of Bonds, or Impriſonments, within thy bowels, O Nation? How often has the Scripture been fulfilled within thy Borders, <hi>Truth is fallen in the Streets, and Equity cannot enter, and Iudgment is turned away backward, and he that departeth from evil, and reproveth Sin in the Gate, maketh himſelf a prey, and becomes a ſigne and a wonder to an evil gainſaying and adulterous Generation:</hi> And the Lord ſaw it: yea, and hath ſeen it; and it diſpleaſed, and yet diſpleaſeth him, becauſe there is no judgment, as in the Ancient dayes; A Lamentation, Wo, and Alas for thee, O <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>O Shrewsbury!</hi> Lo thy crying Sins (together with the multitude and variety of thy Abominations) have reached Heaven, even up to the very Throne of God: and verily his Eternall Eye from above hath beheld, and looked down, and to his wounding hath long (and many a) time refrained himſelf, and ſent his Word of Life, in his Lambs, freely to warn and viſit thee, to Eternal Judgment and Salvation; Wherefore</p>
            <p>Let the Wilde, Brutiſh, Unſtable, Double-minded, Hard<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hearted Inhabitants, within their Dark Habitations of Cruelty, and of thy ſtrong Holds, O SALLOP; O <hi>Sodome,</hi> Remember, and forget it not, if happily yet it may be for their good; Before your Day paſſe away over your heads, even as the Wind, which bloweth where it liſteth (and Lo the ſound you have heard) yet it obeyeth the Lord: But, Do Ye yet know, (O Ye Men, without a good and perfect underſtanding, whom my ſoul pittieth) from whence it cometh, or whether it goeth? Yet, Bleſſed are, and ſhall they be, that Read, and lay it to heart for good.</p>
            <p>But to return to what I was ſpeaking of before, Know Ye, O Magiſtrates, and Inhabitants of this City, again, That the
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:54582:7"/> Teſtimonies of the Swearers that riſe up againſt me are wickedly falſe, and therefore judged and condemned with the True, Eternal, and Spiritual Light, Chriſt in me, and not any other, but the ſame that lighteth every man that cometh into the World; and the True Living God who is Light knoweth, and behold I teſtifie again, that I had not, no not ſo much as an evil thought in my heart againſt any man, from the time I began to ſound forth my Meſſage, which the God of heaven put into my heart, to ſound freely forth (whether people can believe me or not) which, in obedience to the Lord I freely did declare, till I was violently pulled off the Beaſt I rode on, nay, nor then neither: But as to what theſe Wicked men have falſly ſworn againſt me, again I ſay, Lo, I am even as a Babe born as it were but yeſterday, and its my deſire in the truth and nakedneſſe of my heart, if haply they may find a place of Repentance unto Life, and that they, and all may be warned from henceforth not to do, act, or ſpeak contrary to the Light of Jeſus in their Conſciences; and that what theſe men have done againſt me may not then be laid to their charge, who ſimply have not known what they have done; for they have hated me without cauſe, <hi>Father forgive them that know not what they do;</hi> and let them know, My Innocency ſtands juſtified, and not condemned, before the pure preſence and Throne of God, the Light, the Judg of all. Whether you, O men, can believe me, or not, its even ſo; though I am with, and among many Brethren, Sons and Daughters of the ſame Family, or Houſhold of Faith condemned of wicked, ungodlike, unreaſonable men, who are out of the Faith of Gods Elect, thats a Myſtery held in a pure conſcience, and reſpects no mans perſons without which Faith its impoſſible to pleaſe the Living God: and thus it hath happened from Generation to Generation, they who were out of the Faith of Gods Elect, in the reſpect of perſons, giving and receiving honour, with flattering Titles, one to another, which is from beneath, earthly and ſenſual, and not that which is from above, True, Heavenly, Eternal, and Spiritual, alwayes ſince the beginning hated, and perſecuted them that were born of the Spiritual Birth, from above; and ſo it is at this day, That which is born of the Fleſh is Fleſh, and from beneath, perſecutes, that Birth that is
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:54582:8"/> born of the Spirit, which is Spiritual, Heavenly, and from above and not from beneath, or of the world, that lyeth in wickedneſſe; and therefore do they hate us without a cauſe, even as they did Gods Lamb, who is our perfect and compleat Example, and Captain, even of our Salvation: So that we marvel not at the matter, to ſee or feel the Birth born of the Fleſh, Death, and Hell, thats from beneath, perſecute that of the Spirit of Life, from above.</p>
            <p>And behold, it cometh to paſſe, That the true Witneſſe in your Conſciences, and alſo in many more in <hi>Englands</hi> Nation, (the Land of my Nativity, or Place where my firſt birth was begotten, and brought forth, and as a cloud conſumed away, and dyed, yet behold I live) ſhall be awakened, and ariſe to juſtifie, and not condemn; and anſwer to the words of my Teſtimony, given forth, and declared now, and within thy Gates, O City <hi>Worceſter,</hi> wherein I delivered forth the Meſſage which the Lord of heaven had put into my heart, to give forth <hi>A certain ſound and warning</hi> to thy Inhabitants, <hi>O bloody City,</hi> of the mighty, terrible, and Glorious Day of God come, and coming, even a Reſurrection Day: and behold, its begun to dawn, and break forth in <hi>England</hi> firſt, and it's ſhining forth over all Nations, <hi>(Bleſſed is the eye that beholds it.)</hi> And this Day is and will be <hi>a day <hi>of joy,</hi> a day of <hi>peace,</hi> a day of <hi>Gladneſſe of heart,</hi> and of <hi>eternal Life</hi>
               </hi> to all the upright in heart, that turneth from Ungodlineſſe (the Darkneſſe:) But, on the contrary, it is <hi>a Day,</hi> and yet will be <hi>a Day of <hi>Vengeance,</hi>
               </hi> a Day of <hi>Calamity</hi> and <hi>Diſtreſſe,</hi> and <hi>Perplexity,</hi> a Day of <hi>Wo,</hi> and <hi>Miſery,</hi> a Day of <hi>Blackneſſe</hi> and <hi>Darkneſſe,</hi> and of <hi>Aſtoniſhment <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>art;</hi> yea, a Day of <hi>burning,</hi> even in the bowells of ſuch that reject the day of their viſitation, who turn not from Ungodlineſſe, and ſo bring not forth Fruits meet for Repentance, which I alſo freely cryed within thy Gates, O City: And this is the meſſage of the Lord, in the Name of the Lord, and not in my own, to the Inhabitants of this City, as I declared, to be fulfilled in its ſeaſon: And furthermore, this Day of the Lord, which is the Light of our Lord Jeſus Chriſt, the true Light by whom the World was made, who lighteth every man that cometh into the world, (and is the way prepared before the face
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:54582:8"/> of all People,) and this everlaſting Light of the Lord Jeſus Chriſt, as I declared, is breaking forth, and ſhining over all the Nations, and is to awaken the Witneſſe of God in every mans Conſcience; So that, according to its Teſtimony, in every man, even ſo ſhall every mans words, thoughts, and wayes, and Actions be tryed and judged, juſtified or condemned. Wherefore, as I ſaid, and yet ſay, The Witneſſe of God (which is the Light of Jeſus, and not of the Natural man, carnal, or darkneſs) in every Conſcience of the Inhabitants of this City, and of the Nations of the Earth is to, and may be awakened, and ariſe to judgment, and to guide people in the way of Peace, Love, and Unity with God, and one with another, and with the whole Creation, and to do unto all men (in this good old way the Light) as they would be done by, and to ſpeak the Truth every man from his heart to his Neighbour: And verily, if people come not to be exerciſed in this good old way of Light, and Life, whatſoever they do and may profeſs, or be called in words, all their Religion is and may be vain, for this is the Law of the Prophets, according to the ſaying of Jeſus, <hi>Mathew</hi> 7. and the Love that fulfills it, is the Light in the Heart, and the Light is of God, <hi>and that which may be known of God is manifeſt in them, for God hath ſhewed it unto them;</hi> and ſo the people ſhall all be taught of God, who is a Spirit, to worſhip him in it, who is Light, to walk in it, who is Love, to love God again, and one another; and not to kill, or devour, but to love neighbour as ſelf, as ſaith the Holy Scripture.</p>
            <p>And, Moreover the time is a at hand, and behold it cometh to paſſe, That it will be more tolerable for them called <hi>Turks, Infidels,</hi> and <hi>Heathens,</hi> then for many of the Inhabitants of this City; and of <hi>Englands</hi> profeſſing and profane Inhabitants, whoſe life doth not ſhew it ſelf like the <hi>Apoſtles;</hi> and let as ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny as deſire to have a right and good Underſtanding, to diſcern the ground and cauſe of my Sufferings.</p>
            <p>Together with many more of my Dear Friends in this City, and throughout the Nation, let Them with a meek Spirit, and in the fear of the Lord, deliberately (and not haſtily) read this throughout, and ſuffer the True Witneſſe to ariſe, to anſwer to the ſame Teſtimony from whence the words come; and know,
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:54582:9"/> that according to, and after this manner, the words of my Teſtimony was declared in the 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Month, the 20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day, without and within thy Gates, O City: And after that, Men that feared not God, did beat, and alſo wickedly threatned often to take away my Life, as one called Captain <hi>Thornbury</hi> did, many times, with his ſword drawn, directed and put towards my breaſt, and to thruſt it into my Guts, as he threatned many and divers times, with wicked and deſperate ſwearing, and curſing, not becoming a Souldier, or the Spirit of a man, an <hi>Engliſhman,</hi> to a naked man that neither ſpake nor thought evil againſt any one man, woman, or childes perſon, upon the face of the whole earth; He that ſearcheth my heart knoweth its even ſo. And while he, the ſaid Captain <hi>Thornbury</hi> (ſo call'd) had cauſed my body to be halled, dragged, and abuſed, and to be thrown from place to place in the Street of the City, breathing out his cruel, vile threatnings, together with bloody Oaths, and curſed Speakings which thereby ſtrengthened the hands of many wilde,brutiſh and ungodlike men, women, and Children, whileſt I was among them in the meekneſſe, and ſtrength of God, even as a Lamb, among a company of Ravenous, Wilde-beaſts, Bears, Lions, and devouring Wolves, bereaved of their whelps; and as they were after this manner drawing me before the Judgment-ſeat, ſome crying out, <hi>Knock out his brains before he goes any further,</hi> and many ſuch like cruel threat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nings and revilings, doing violence. <note place="margin">O ye Rulers, forget not, but remember the wickedneſs acted by them called Mountebanks, many dayes acting wickedneſſe, within the City, notwithſtanding they were warned by ſundry of the ſervants of the Lord, in the 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Month, 1660. who were halled, bearen, and abuſed for the ſame. Furthermore, one of theſe, called Mountebanks, acting wickedneſs after their accuſtom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed manner, folly, and madneſs, upon a ſtage, in the open ſtreet, of the City, with his face almoſt all black, with a Crown upon his head. And what is this, a honour, or diſhonour to the King, O Ye Magiſtrates? But what has, your ſword been laid upon this Tranſgreſſor yet? And, Is not this, and Bull-baiting, together with the abuſe of the poor Creatures of God, and ſuch like madneſſe, and Revellings, and Abominations. Are not theſe things a great diſhonour to the God of Heaven, to the King, to you, and your City. O ye Rulers, in meckneſs Conſider, and hold forth your ſword, and let your eyes be open to ſee, where to lay it, leſt the Lord require it at your hands. Theſe are the words of God to Ye, through his Priſoner. D. B.</note> A lamentation ſounded in my heart for the, Sober Inhabitants of this City: And, Lo, the Spirit of the Lord within me ſhewed me, how it was with <hi>Jonah</hi> and the <hi>Nenivites;</hi> how that they ſuffered him to deliver his Meſſage, and to cry, when
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:54582:9"/> he entred into the great City <hi>Ninevy,</hi> a dayes journey: and behold, The Prophane Inhabitants of this City would not ſuffer me, with my precious life in my hand (which I had received power to lay it down, and to take it again) to obey the Lord of Heaven, hardly half an hour to cry againſt Sin, and to declare Glad-Tidings, and to warn them freely to Repentance, as before expreſt. And, Whileſt my minde was thus meditating in the Counſell of God, whileſt they were threatning and drawing this body in which I am before the Judgment Seat, the good Spirit of the Lord, the Holy God, in me, rather juſtified the men of <hi>Ninevy,</hi> than the hard-hearted, blood-thirſty men of this City. And Lo, this Cry immediatly run through me, <hi>(viz.) <hi>That the men of Ninevy ſhall ariſe up in Iudgment againſt this Generation.</hi>
               </hi>
            </p>
            <p>And Friend, and Friends, Know Ye again, That after this manner the words of my Teſtimony were ſounded forth through me, even as the good Spirit of the Lord, in my heart gave me utterance, to which my Soul is become ſubject <hi>(Glory to the God of Truth)</hi> and (Lo) I rather choſe to fear, and obey God, than man that ſhall dye, and to be condemned of the world that lyeth in wickedneſs, rather than to be condemned of the Lord by his Witneſſe, the Light of Everlaſting Life, of Righteouſneſſe revealed in me: Yet I am ſubject to every Ordinance of Man, for the Lords ſake, <hi>Active</hi> or <hi>Paſſive;</hi> (to be plain, thus) <hi>Active,</hi> in obedience to the Ordinances of Man, that are Juſt, Equal, or Equi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table, Wholeſome, and Reaſonable, founded on, and accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the Righteous, Equall, Royal Law of God, which is ſo juſt; and alſo <hi>Paſſive,</hi> by ſuffering under the contrary, as a Teſtimony againſt it, and them that miniſters it forth, in its many and Various Appearances: And, This many Hundreds that fear and obey the God of Truth with me, (in the ſtrength of Jeſus, the Light that ſaves us from Sinnes) Do even for the Lords ſake.</p>
            <pb n="20" facs="tcp:54582:10"/>
            <p>And through thy Gate, and Street, O CITY, the ſound words of the Living Teſtimony of God, in this his mighty Day hath entred, and even into the Ears and Hearts alſo of many of thy Inhabitants, whether they love to retain or keep the wholſome Sayings, or not, or hear or forbear; yet, bear with me, and liſten O Ye Inhabitants of this CITY, and hearken, O all ye Inhabitants of <hi>ENGLAND,</hi> and of the <hi>NATIONS</hi> afarr off, to whom this ſhall come, and give ear to the words of a True Friend, even to the whole Creation of God, and to the ſoul of every Man, of Male or Female, that lieth under the Bondage of Corruption, and groans for Deliverance, to be brought into the Glorious Liberty, which is the true Liberty, the ſame that was in the Beginning, the Dominion, and Perfect Freedome of the Sons of God. Let the Meek, Wiſe in heart anſwer me.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Worceſter</hi> Priſon, <date>this 9th Month, the 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day, at even: and of the Year accounted, 1660.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>D. B.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="affidavit">
            <head>Here followeth a true Relation of ſeveral Perſons, who heard what was declared by <hi>Daniel Baker,</hi> the <hi>20th</hi> of the <hi>Moneth</hi> called <hi>October, (1660)</hi> through part of this City, ſome of which heard him from the begining untill he was forced off the Beaſt that he did ride on; and their Teſtimonies are as followeth.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>Imprimis, FRances,</hi> the Wife of <hi>John Roſe</hi> heard him declare from the beginning unto the end: And her Teſtimony is, <hi>That he did warn the people to Repent, for Deſtruction and Miſery was near at hand,</hi> and ſuch like ſound Exhortations, but not any thing againſt the King, or any other Perſon.</p>
            <pb n="21" facs="tcp:54582:10"/>
            <p>
               <hi>Anne,</hi> the VVife of <hi>John VVinfield,</hi> heard him ſpeak, thar <hi>The Dreadfull Day, or a Terrible Day was near at hand,</hi> or to this purpoſe; but not any thing that was hurtfull to any mans perſon.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Henry Dyſon,</hi> his Teſtimony is, that he ſpake to this purpoſe that, <hi>A Gloomy and Dark Day was at hand, but a Day of Gladneſs to them that fear the Lord;</hi> and exhorted people to repent.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>William Till</hi> heard him ſpeak to this purpoſe, that, <hi>Wo is to the Wicked, or to ſuch who love Sin, but unto them that did deny Ungodlineſſe, a Day of Peace;</hi> with many other Godly Admonitions.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Robert Smith</hi> heard him ſay, that, <hi>A Day of wo and Aſtoniſhment was at hand, but a day of Gladneſs and joy to the Upright in heart:</hi> witneſs, <hi>Elizabeth Smith.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Richard Till</hi> ſaid, that he heard him counſel the people, to <hi>Repent, for the Kingdome of God was at hand:</hi> but not any thing touching the Rulers of this Kingdome.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Philip Bearcroft</hi> and <hi>Edborough</hi> his Wife heard him exhort the Inhabitants <hi>to be awakened, for the day of God was nigh.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I <hi>Robert Edwards</hi> reſtifie, That the Man that declared in the Street, from the Croſs to the Place where he was pulled off the Horſe, I was an Eye-witneſs, an ear witneſs of his riding, and of his behaviour, in his declaring, as I went from the Croſs, near to him, within the hearing of him all the way. And he ſpake nothing touching the King nor of his Majeſty, nor of Tyrant, nor Uſurper, nor of the Nation, nor Nations, nor Government, nor Governours, <hi>Rob. Edwards.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Dorothy Martine,</hi> and <hi>Margaret Drue,</hi> they heard him ſay, <hi>That the Light was a ſhining forth, and that it would ſhine forth more and more, and that the Day of the Lord was at hand: But nothing againſt the King, His Government, or any ones perſon.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Thomas Garret</hi>'s Teſtimony is this, that he heard him ſay, that, <hi>Chriſt was a ſhining forth in the Nation:</hi> and that, <hi>he warned people to Repent:</hi> and that, <hi>the Day of Judgment was at hand, but nothing againſt the King, his Government, or any mans perſon.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="22" facs="tcp:54582:11"/>
            <p>And divers others, who were VVitneſses of what <hi>D. B.</hi> ſaid, their Teſtimony may be produced, who heard him ſpeak words to the ſame purpoſe, who heard nothing ſpoken by him againſt the King, or Government, or the perſon of any one.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>D. B.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
